Hello everyone welcome to my
demo of cloud portfolio
Platform so here we already
talked about the
Git repository git action we saw
also the work load identity
Federation and IAM service
account in Firebase hosting and
Now we're going to see the cloud
Dns manager
Some and why I implemented it
Dns secured here also it's
enabled I enabled it for this
Platform so I decided to use the
cloud dns with dns security
Enabled because adds a
protection against
Dns tampering usually if you
want to add layer of security on
Our website we have to add also
a CAA record to explicitly
define which
Certificate authorities are
allowed to issue certificates
For domain so these are small
Controls but they are so
important to reduce attacks that
We can we can perceive against
our
Website so it's important to
protect the integrity of our
Networking and also besides the
implementation of the
CAA record we
Have on other side a
storage cloud
Storage where we can find some
videos
That are stored on
google separated the the storage
In two buckets so we have a two
Buckets the first one contains a
public video asset used by the
Website since those files don't
need to stay the most expensive
Storage style forever I also use
a life cycle policy to move all
The object to cheaper tier after
Days so and the other bucket is
the state
Bucket this one contains the
Terraform state it's a private
Version and protected against
accidental deletion so it cannot
Be deleted because it contains
very important information about
our project and setup
And then we have at the
bottom the Terraform as we can
See here we have
Terraform here this is what ties
the all architecture
Together I chose Terraform to be
my
Code
infrastructure so everything you
See on these diagram like
Am identity
Federation austin dns storage and
many other tools I define
As a code and manage it through
version
Control so so I'm depending on
the sequence of manual I'm not
Depending on the sequence of
manual clicks everything in this
Platform is
automated it's completely
Automated in this
Platform and beside all of these
services that we saw here we
Have also
Monitoring observability and
alerting
Here so we can
Monitor our application so in
this case is the
Platform so at the final I need
I want to know when something up
Will goes wrong every 5 minutes
I can up time check verifies
that the site is responding with
Up time check and also I have
the alert policy and
Notification channel email that
I can receive any alert if
something goes wrong with the
Platform so I have automated the
deployment instead of manual
Releases short-lived
credentials instead of permanent
Permanent keys I have a least privilege access instead of
Broad permission I have a globally delivered hosting instead of a
Single point of failure and a versioned state here
Versioned state instead of
unmanaged
Infrastructure the reason that
I chose this
Architecture I wanted something
that will be secure by
Design easy to
reproduce inexpensive to
Operate and very realistic
enough to demonstrate how
I would approach infrastructure
in a professional
Environment so thank you very
much for watching
This demo see you in the next
Week thank you